# **MARK LOVEJOY**

# Frontend Developer

Newcastle Upon Tyne 07804 519 312

marklovejoydev@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/marklovejoydev github.com/marklovejoydev

#### **PROFILE**

Junior Frontend Developer with an aptitude for personal development and problem solving. A methodical customer focus approach to work and a strong drive to see things through to completion, hands on approach with a high drive and passion for success through effective communication and a collaborative approach with teams, which when implemented provides greater results. With a focus on user interface elements and user experience using React, HTML, CSS and JavaScript in the client.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

• Language: JavaScript

• Frontend: React, HTML5, CSS3, Frameworks (MUI, Bootstrap)

Backend: Express, SQL, Postgres, NodeJS

Testing: Jest

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# Trainee Software Developer | Northcoders | May 23 - Aug 23

Northcoders Full Stack Software Developer course covering HTML CSS and JavaScript in the initial week then progressing onto cover test-driven development, pair programming, object-oriented programming and a range of other core tools and workplace practices through the medium of JavaScript.

Using Node.js to run code for the back end and focus on ways of dealing with asynchronous programming. Then look at APIs to gather data through multiple methods of public APIs or create my own database with Express and SQL and host my own API.

Using Frameworks such as React and understand how to use and pass data through components by controlling the virtual DOM to make updates more dynamic by re-rendering components rather than the page for a better user experience.

# **Projects**

- News API: https://nc-news-ml.onrender.com/api GitHub: marklovejoydev/nc-news
- News React Frontend: <a href="https://nc-news-ml.netlify.app">https://nc-news-ml.netlify.app</a> GitHub: <a href="marklovejoydev/nc-news-fe">marklovejoydev/nc-news-fe</a>
- Team Project –Demo: Who's Doing the Dishes GitHub: who-is-doing-the-dishes-app

Team based project learning a new language and framework utilizing pair programming and version control with GitHub to maximize efficient code.

My Portfolio page - <a href="https://mark-lovejoy-portfolio.netlify.app/">https://mark-lovejoy-portfolio.netlify.app/</a>

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Tactical Air Controller | Royal Air Force | July 2016 - Aug 2023

While being attached to another organisation within H. M. Forces as a Tactical Air Control Party Signaller (TACP) has given me the opportunity to develop my current skill set and pass on my experience to a greater range of individuals working with high value assets, meeting training objectives and delivering a high level of training and experiences to the wider force.

# Areas including:

- · Routing and safety of flight
- Air to ground deconfliction
- Precision strikes

During a NATO multi-national exercise an opportunity was presented for myself to communicate the capabilities and limitations of aircraft used within Close Air Support (CAS) to high-ranking international commanders which had an impactful effect on the mission and during the execution phase I was a consultant for dynamic situations that came forward. Along with collecting analytical data for weather in order to assist with data being transferred for aircraft.

# **MILITARY SKILLS**

- Leadership / Team Development / TRiM Practitioner
- Security Operative / Communications Specialist & Maintainer
- Radio Operator / TACP / Weapons Specialist
- Armoured Vehicle Driver / Advanced First Aid (Team Medic)

#### **FUNCTIONAL SKILLS & TRAINING**

- Health and safety in the workplace
- Risk management training
- Team leader & adult instructor
- Security cleared

# Assistant Manager | Coral Bookmakers | Aug 2014 - July 2016

I held responsibility and accountability over 4 members of staff in which sales targets of promotions was directed making deadlines for sales and achieving targets part of the daily routine.

Due to the amount of money changing hands a high attention for detail along with the being fast and efficient are strong characteristics that every member of staff required. With health and safety, risk management and customer relations it was my job to train, maintain and motivate staff that was incredibly rewarding.

Previous experience available on request.

# **EDUCATION**

Hookergate Comprehensive School | Sept 2001 – June 2008

# **Qualifications Achieved**

A-Level: Design & Technology - Grade D

AS-Level: Design & Technology - Grade B